Oh, see you
in the choir on Sunday!
嘿, 礼拜天教堂见喔
Hi, Mike.
嗨  麦克
Hello?
你好？
Hi.
嗨
Oh, hi.
哦，嗨
Been home long?
你没出门吗
No. I just got back
from the store.
不  我刚从店里回来
We're looking forward
to tonight.
很期盼今晚的会面
Can I bring anything?
要我带些什么过去吗
I think I have
everything.
不用了  我不缺
Well, if there's
anything...
好吧  如果有任何需要...
Wait.
There is something.
等等  是有个东西...
Do you have any
champagne glasses?
可以带些香槟酒杯过来吗
I thought we'd start
with champagne.
我想我们可以喝点香槟
We have some.
嗯  我这里有杯子
Do you have eight?
有八只吗
No. We have six.
不  只有六只
Bring them. Mitch and I
will drink from jelly glasses.
带过来吧  米契跟我用水杯就可以了
You're going
to such trouble.
那就麻烦你了
I always go to lots of
trouble for a dinner party.
我总是去参加一个晚宴的麻烦。
I've got to run.
弄晚餐都是这样子的
See you
around 8:00. Bye.
八点钟见  再见
Bye.
再见
Look at this floor.
看看地板
I thought you love
chocolate chip cookies.
我以为你喜欢吃巧克力饼干
Where's that book
I gave you?
我给你的那本书呢
When I was a little girl,
这可是我小时候
this was my favorite book.
我最喜爱的书
Which one was
your favorite story?
你最喜欢哪一则故事呢
What difference
does it make?
喜不喜欢有屁用吗
Let me out of here! Help!
让我出去  救命啊
It's been so long,
已经好久了
I almost
can't remember them.
几乎不记得书上的故事了
Help! Let me out!
救命啊  放我出去
What are you doing?
你要干嘛
Just preheating
to 350.
调到350度啊
Help! Help! There's
a crazy woman here!
来人  救命啊  这女人疯了
She's going to cook me!
她要煮熟我
She's going
to eat me! Help!
她想要吃掉我  救命啊
I never could do
long division.
从来没这样做过除法
Let's see.
我看看
How many times
does 12 go into 75?
75除以12是多少?
Oh... 6 times,
3 left over.
嗯   是6  余数是3
Why?
要干嘛?
Well, at 12 minutes
a pound,
喔  每磅要烤12分钟
that means you have
to be in the oven
也就是说把你放进烤箱的时间
by no later than...
不能晚于...
1:30.
下午一点半
Oh...
哦...
but evisceration takes
at least an hour.
但刨除最少还需要一个小时
Evisceration?
刨除?
What's that?
什么?
It's like gutting a fish.
就像杀鱼一样啊
First you make
a long slit,
首先  要用刀长长的划开
then remove everything
that isn't meat...
除了肉之外  其他都要剥除
the heart, the lungs,
the intestines, and so forth.
心啊  肺啊
肠子  有的没的
Then you fill it back up
with stuffing,
然后填上馅料
sew it back together
with one of these.
再用线缝起来
Maybe I should
get started now.
也许现在应该要开始了
Wait. There's
plenty of time.
等一下  还有一些时间
This was
your favorite book.
这是你最喜欢的书。
Don't you want
to hear a story?
你不想听故事吗？
A love story?
一个爱情故事？
Yeah!
Well, not really.
是啊   不一定啦
But it's a really
good one.
但这是一个超棒的故事
You'll like it
a lot.
你会喜欢的
Here.
这里
It's about these
guys in college.
这是一群同伴人在大学的故事
They live
in the same dorm.
他们住在同一栋宿舍
And one of them's
kind of poor,
其中有一个穷小子
so he works his way
through school selling things.
他利用学校赚点外快
Hey!
嘿！
Be careful with that.
小心搬运
His name's Bellingham,
他叫做贝林汉
and he collects antiques.
他搜集古董
Well, one day,
有一天
Bellingham got
a very special delivery.
贝林汉收到一个特别的包裹
Meanwhile, the other guys...
Andy and Lee...
同一时间  其他的同伴
安迪跟李...
they were real rich.
他们家很富有
And they did something
very nasty to Bellingham.
他们对贝林汉做了很下流的事
Lee, the most work
you've done
李  大部分的事你都完成了
in four years
of college
四年的大学生涯
is filling out that application
for the Penrose Fellowship.
总算可以拿到"潘罗斯奖学金"了
Hey...
嘿
hard work pays off,
Andy,
努力是有收获的  安迪
especially when
you have a girlfriend
尤其是你  还交女朋友
who can write
award-winning essays
谁还有空写获奖论文
about why I want to spend
the summer traveling Europe.
这就是为什么我花整个暑假
待在欧洲的原因
I suppose my sister's
pretty smart.
我想我妹妹十分聪明
She's just not
very honest.
虽然她不太老实
I don't see why
you'd risk it.
我不明白为何你敢冒这个险
If they learn she wrote
the proposal for you,
如果他们发现
是她帮你写的
they'll kick you out.
你会被学校赶出去的
Your family sends you to Europe
every summer anyway,
反正你家每年夏天
都送你去欧洲
so I don't understand.
我真的不懂
Ah.
啊
But this way I have
the fellowship money
但这是我赚钱的方法
to bring back
a Maserati.
才能把玛莎拉蒂带回来
Maserati.
玛莎拉蒂
Guess who was
my main competitor
猜猜看我的竞争者是谁
for the Penrose.
跟我竞争奖学金的
You know Bellingham works
part-time at the university museum.
你知道贝林汉在学校博物馆打工
Where Susan does
volunteer work. I know.
- 也就是苏珊当志工的地方
- 我知道
You better hope
he doesn't find out
最好希望别被他发现
she helped you screw him
out of that fellowship.
她帮你把他搞垮
让他拿不到奖学金的事
Bellingham has
the hots for Susan.
你不知道贝林汉很迷恋苏珊?
Don't worry.
We'll be fine.
别担心  没事的
Ah, Andy.
嗨  安迪
Ah, Edward.
嗨  艾德华
How you doing?
你好吗？
You going to introduce me
to your friend?
不把我介绍给你朋友?
Uh, yeah.
嗯...
This is...
这是
Lee... Monckton,
right?
李...蒙克顿  对吧?
Yeah.
是啊。
Yeah. I, uh,
saw your picture
我见过你的照片
in our illustrious
college newspaper.
就在学校校刊上
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Oh... thank you.
哦，谢谢
It's an odd coincidence,
us meeting,
说来也很巧
since we're
in competition
我们正在竞争
for the Penrose
Fellowship.
争取潘罗斯奖学金
Oh, wait, wait.
You said it.
喔  等等  你说...
Competition.
Somebody...
竞争...总是会有人
has to win, you know.
赢得的  你知道的
Not always
the better man.
但不会老让某个人赢吧
Oh, no, no, no, no.
不不不不
Allow me.
我来吧
Hey, thanks.
嘿，谢谢
That lot 249
was a heavy mother.
249那一箱很重喔  小心啊
You'll get your money
back tomorrow.
明天我会把钱还你的
Oh, there's no rush.
喔  不急不急
Uh...
这样吧  艾德华
I'll tell you what,
Edward.
带我们参观一下
Just show us
what you have in there,
让我朋友开开眼界
and my friend here
will write it off.
我的朋友在这里会写下来。
All right.
没问题
If lot 249 lives up
to my expectations,
假如249那一箱
符合我期望的话
it won't matter that I was cheated
out of the Penrose.
既使被搞掉了奖学金  也无所谓的
Cheated?
被搞掉?
Something unfortunate
happened to me
有些倒楣事发生在我身上
before
the committee
就在开委员会前
announced
its decision.
他们宣布了一件事
What?
什么事
I was accused
of stealing
就是我被控告偷窃
a pre-Columbian Zuni fetish
from the museum.
说我从博物馆偷了
Well...
原住民文物
did you?
那你有偷吗
I loathe Zuni aesthetics.
我最讨厌原住民文物
But by the time
I was cleared,
那时候  我就被除名
the committee decided
in your favor.
委员会才决定提名你
Oh.
哦。
Well, who was it
that accused you?
到底是谁指控你的?
It was
an anonymous tip.
那是匿名检举
Oh!
噢!
I should probably
get going.
我应该走了
Susan's waiting
at home for me.
苏珊正在家里等我
Absolutely not.
当然不行
You're not leaving here
你还不能离开
until you see
what's inside lot 249.
等到你看见箱子里的东西后再走
That was the deal.
这是刚才说好的
Edward, why would you
buy something like this?
艾德华  你怎会买下这种东西?
I wasn't born with a silver
trust fund in my mouth.
因为我不是
天生含着金汤匙出生的
You... You can actually
sell this to somebody...
你...确定这东西
卖得掉吗
for a profit?
就这种石像?
What else
would I sell it for?
除了这个  我还能卖什么呢
Give me a hand.
来帮个忙
My...
天啊
God, Andy,
老天啊  安迪
it looks just like
your father.
看起来好像你爸爸
Ew!
恶
It stinks like rotten flowers.
味道很像腐烂的植物
Let's see if the embalmers
did him any justice.
来看看里面放了什么防腐剂
You're going
to unwrap it?
你当真要割开吗
Why not?
为何不
All you're
looking at
来看看这价值..
is 3,000 years
of dry rot.
三千年的遗迹
I'm going to be late.
I'm going to...
我要迟到了  得走了
I'll show you out.
我送你
See you later, Andy?
晚点见  安迪?
Yeah.
好的
4, 5, over.
4，5，over。
6. Two more.
6。两个。
You're back early.
你回来的真"早"啊
We quit after two sets.
我们延长了赛程
Sounds like we lost
to Andy again.
听起来好像又输给安迪了
Do you know what
your brother is doing
你知道  你哥现在在做什么吗
right now
as we speak?
就在我们谈话之时?
Huh?
呃?
He's unwrapping
a mummy!
他在割开木乃伊
With Edward Fucking Bellingham!
跟那个该死的艾德华贝林汉
How much did
you tell Andy?
你告诉了安迪多少事?
Uh...
嗯...
that... that... that
you wrote the essay.
就说....是你写的论文
Oh.
哦
Well, that's okay.
那还好
He knows I do
all your papers anyway.
反正他早就知道这件事
Oh, and then... and then,
还有那个...
Bellingham
casually mentioned
贝林汉还提到
that someone dropped an
anonymous tip about the stolen...
有人匿名检举他偷窃
Pre-Columbian
Zuni fetish?
什么中美洲原住民文物之类的
He's guessing.
他乱猜的
Well, maybe, but I think
Andy knows it was you.
也许吧  但我想安迪知道是你干的
Andy's my brother.
他是我哥哥
He won't do anything.
他不会对我怎样的
And Bellingham's
a loser.
况且贝林汉输掉了
He can't do anything.
他不敢怎样的
I've really got to
get ready for dinner.
我要去赴晚餐的约了
Don't you want
to see his face?
不想看看他的脸吗
No. Thank you.
不了  多谢
He looks pissed off.
他看起来好像很生气
Like he's thinking.
像是在想事情的模样
He's not thinking
anything.
他没有在想事情
The first thing
the embalmers did
是因为防腐的程序
was stick a hook
up his nose,
要先用钩子把鼻子缝起来
then drag his brain out
through his nostrils.
然后把线拖到大脑  穿过鼻孔
Here's where they cut him open
to remove his innards.
你看这里  他们把内脏全取出
Then they stuff him
with flowers and spices.
然后用鲜花及香料填进去
Here, hold this open.
来  帮我拉开
Come on,
hold this open.
来啊   拉开它
Ohh.
喔
Myrrh.
有没药
Cassia.
决明子。
Onions.
洋葱。
And...
嗯...
What?
Onions and what?
洋葱 ... 还有什么?
A fortune cookie.
幸运符
What does it say?
写了 些什么
Uh...
呃...
I have no idea.
我不知道。
Do you know how to read
Third Kingdom hieroglyphics?
你懂第三帝国的象形文字吗
You're taking those books
back to the library now?
你现在要把书拿去图书馆吗
They're three months
overdue.
这些书已经逾期三个月了
And I thought I'd
stop by to see Andy
我也想顺便去看看安迪
on the way home.
回程的时候
You don't care about
those books or Andy.
你才不在意书跟安迪
You're going to
go see Bellingham.
你根本是想去找贝林汉
I give him a hard-on.
怎么可能?
我老是刁难他
I'll talk to him,
throw him off the track.
我还告诉他  叫他去死耶
Zuni fetish.
文化古物
Hmm.
嗯
They use their second timeout.
他们利用终场前的两分钟
I've never
seen Johnny
我从来没看过强尼
so enraged by
a defensive play.
那么有活力的防卫动作
He's arguing at
the scorer's table.
现在他正在跟裁判争论中
They call a technical
on Scott!
他们说是技术性犯规
"Grow, o light.
"燃烧吧  光芒"
"Come forth, o light.
"来吧  光芒"
"Rise, o light.
"升起吧  光芒"
" Ascend, o light.
"传递吧  光芒"
"O darkness, remove thyself
from before him.
"在他的面前  把黑暗抹去"
"Open his eyes.
"睁开他的眼睛"
That bastard can
read that scroll.
那浑球又在念咒语
"Open, tat.
"苏醒吧"
"Open, nap.
"Open his eyes.
"睁开他的眼睛"
"O darkness, remove thyself
from before him.
"在他的面前  把黑暗抹去"
"Open his eyes.
"睁开他的眼睛"
"The eater of shadows,
"食影者"
"the eater of souls,
"食魂者"
"open his eyes.
"睁开他的眼睛"
"Open, tat.
"苏醒吧"
"Open, nap.
Open his eyes."
"睁开他的眼睛"
Oh, jeez!
老天啊
Hey, Bellingham!
嘿  贝林汉
Hey, Bellingham, come on.
贝林汉   麻烦一下
The fuse box is
right outside your door.
电箱在你的房门口
Christ.
天啊
Come on, Bellingham.
It's the end of the playoffs.
别这样  贝林汉
别再玩了
I mean, Christ.
我说真的  啊～～
Oh.
哦
God.
神
Hey.
嘿
You okay?
你没事吧
Yeah.
嗯
Jesus!
糟糕
What the hell
are you doing here?
你来这里做什么
I just... I just
thought I'd stop by.
我...只是来拜访一下
What's going on?
Somebody just knocked me down.
怎么回事
有人把我推到在地上
Look, you two
just wait here.
你们两个等着
Don't go after him!
嘿  别追着他
Go after who?
追谁啊
Um...
那个...
a thief.
小偷
Damn fuses.
电箱常坏
Well...
这...
he couldn't
have taken much.
旧宿舍就是这样
Would you like
some brandy?
你要些白兰地吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Did you see him?
有看到他吗
No.
没有
Not really, but he did look
a little weird.
有看到一点点  他看起来有点怪异
Yes, he was very weird.
是啊  他非常的怪
He must've been on drugs.
因为许久没用"药"了
Got off
with my rings.
那人把我的戒指拿走了
Roman stuff.
Hollow gold.
喔  那是 .. 空心K金的罗马古物
At least he didn't get away
with lot 249.
至少他没把249号箱子偷走
No!
不要！
Lee!
李
#...With me #
# That's the way
a heart breaks #
# And every man
must pay the price #
# That's the way
a heart breaks #
# You stand before the gates
of paradise #
# Of fire
and ice ##
Shit.
可恶
This better be important.
最好是重要的事
Need any help, Bill?
需要帮忙吗  比尔
No. It's a mess,
but we got it covered.
不用  真是一团乱
我们已经处理了
Andy.
安迪
You busy?
你在忙吗
Guess I could
use this, huh?
猜猜看我做了什么事  嗯?
I lied to the police.
我对警察撒谎了
I saw who did it.
我看见那个人了
What?
什么？
I saw who
killed Lee.
我看见是谁杀了李
He was thin...
他很瘦
and filthy...
又很脏
and stinking.
也很臭
Like rotten flowers.
闻起来像是臭掉的植物
Lot 249.
249号箱...
Very few thieves
很少小偷
would have the discernment
to realize
会去偷这种东西
that this was
one of the museum's
何况是博物馆的物品
most unusual pieces.
是很不寻常的文物
Susan Smith stole that fetish
and planted it here.
是苏珊史密斯偷的  她栽赃我
Oh, my.
哦，天哪
What a sensual
candlestick.
好美的烛台
Take your hands off that.
别乱碰好吗
Good evening,
Mr. Smith.
晚安  史密斯先生
Dean Murray.
你们好
Andy, do you
know Dr. Carey,
安迪  你认识凯瑞先生吗
the curator of
the university museum?
他是大学博物馆的计划人
Uh...
呃...
hi.
嗨
What's going on,
Edward?
怎么回事  艾德华
I'm a little busy
right now, Andy.
我现在有点忙，安迪。
Yes.
是的
Mr. Bellingham
is packing.
贝林汉先生正在打包
He's leaving
the university.
他要离开学校了
Oh!
噢!
Pity.
好可惜
Would have been
a nice acquisition
如果木乃伊还在的话
if the mummy
had come with it.
应该是很珍贵的
What happened
to the mummy?
那具木乃伊呢
He never did have taste.
真没品味
I don't care how cheap
the psychology is.
我可不在乎那些可笑的心理分析
I still hate these
stupid chrysanthemums.
我还是很讨厌这些该死的菊花
I'm aware of that,
operator.
我明白  接线人员
I've been trying to get
through for a half hour.
我已经打了半个小时的电话
Help!
救命啊
Police!
警察
Please, somebody help me!
有人来救救我吗
Susan!
苏珊
Jesus.
老天啊
老天
Damned fuses.
该死的电箱
Hey!
嘿！
Oh, you're awake.
喔  你醒来了
That's my master's
thesis.
这是我的硕士论文
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Well, I'm going to start
a little fire under your chair
喔  我要在这里生火用的
and roast your nuts.
烧焦你的鸟蛋
Why?
为什么？
Because you
killed my sister
因为你杀了我的妹妹
and my best friend.
和我最好的朋友。
That's why.
这就是为什么
I didn't kill them.
我没有杀死他们
Right. Right.
Your friend lot 249 did.
是啊  你唆使249号去杀的
Ah. I thought
he'd be back.
哈  他回来了
The alleged perpetrator's
got an airtight alibi.
要指控也要有不在场证明吧
He's been dead
for 3,000 years.
他已经死了三千年了。
Then these should make
for excellent kindling.
这些应该足够来点燃了
Oh, Andy, you're crazy.
哦，安迪，你疯了
Ooh, damn, I think
I forgot my matches.
妈的  我竟然忘了火柴
Grow, grow, o light.
燃烧吧  光芒
Ascend, o light.
传递吧  光芒
Rise, o light.
Come forth, o light.
升起吧   向前吧  光芒
O darkness, remove, re...
让黑暗...
Shit, how does it go?
该死，怎么回事？
Remove thyself from them.
将黑暗....抹去
Open, tat. Open, nap.
苏醒吧   苏醒吧
Open his eyes.
睁开眼睛
Open...
睁开他的眼睛
Edward,
艾德华
I believe
in being prepared.
我想一切就绪了
Eh?
嗯？
Batteries in case
those fuses blow again.
等等电箱又要走火了
Need a hand up there,
fella? Huh?
要我扶你起起来吗
老兄   啊?
Jesus.
天啊
Edward...
爱德华...
I'm not going
to apologize
我不想要道歉
for what Lee and Susan
did to you.
尤其是你对他们两人干的事
I won't call the cops either,
because what sane person
我也不会报警
因为没有疯子会相信
would believe that
a 3,000-year-old mummy
是那个三千年前的木乃伊干的
really did come
back to life anyway?
复活过来杀人?
But I do have another idea.
但我另有主意
Well, that takes care
of that, doesn't it?
都处理了  不是吗
Would you untie me,
please?
可以帮我解开了吗
Yeah, of course.
好，当然。
As soon as you tell me
where the scroll is.
只要你告诉我卷轴在哪里
You don't need
the scroll.
你又不需要那东西
It only worked
for that mummy,
那只对木乃伊有效
which you've
totally destroyed.
那个已经被你毁掉的木乃伊
The second drawer in the desk
on the right.
在书桌右边  第二个抽屉里
It's irreplaceable.
这是很珍贵的东西
Yeah,
I certainly hope so.
希望是
That scroll would have made
my entire career.
这卷轴是花了
我一辈子的心血取得的
My sister and my best friend
died because of this.
我妹跟我朋友为了它而死
Killing me won't
bring them back.
既使杀了我 也无法挽回啊
If I let you live,
that will bring them back?
我只要不要有人为此牺牲
Don't worry, Andy.
别担心，安迪。
You'll never
see me again.
你不会再见到我了
But I'll find a way
to keep in touch.
但我会找方法联络到你的
Open, tat.
Open, nap.
苏醒吧  苏醒吧
Bind them both
to my service
把他们两个绑起来  为我服务
and to the gods
of death, terror...
为死神  恐怖的
and revenge.
报复吧
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈
Hey, man, what's so
fucking funny?
嘿  先生  什么那么好笑?
I was just thinking
of this guy I know.
我只是在想一个我认识的朋友
Couldn't distinguish
a Third Dynasty sacred scroll
他竟然把埃及文字的卷轴
当成
from a piece of post-Alexandrian
pictogram porn.
第三帝国象形的卷轴给烧了
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈
哈哈哈哈
Mom, I'll be home as soon
as finals are over.
妈  我会在家温习期末考的功课
Yeah, the funeral
was hard on me, too.
我知道  我也很难过的
No, the police don't
have any leads yet.
不  警方还没抓到人
All right?
好吧
I'll see you
next week.
下周见了
Bye.
拜拜
Andy?
安迪
Bellingham
sends his regards.
贝林汉带口信要给你喔
Antiques
are so fascinating.
古董都是很珍贵美妙的
You told that
very well.
你很会说故事
Thank you.
谢谢。
Goodness,
it's almost 1:00.
现在一点了
We've got to
get things started.
我们得开始做菜了
You know, if I'm
not home by 6:00,
我如果没在六点前回家
they'll come looking.
他们会来找我的
Looking for what,
dear?
找什么呢  亲爱的?
Uh... wait.
等一等
I'll tell you
another story.
我再告诉你  下一个故事
Put the book away.
把书放下
But it's the best
story yet.
但这故事很精彩的
I stopped reading twice
because I got scared.
我被这个故事吓了两次
It's about the old man
who's so rich
是关于一个很有钱的老男人
and lives in this
big house all by himself.
独居在一栋大房子里
Okay. This'll be
the last story,
好吧  这是最后一个故事了
and you have to
make it quick.
你最好讲快一点
I will. I promise.
我会的
It's about this old man
named Drogan.
这是在讲一个叫做多根的老男人
Old man Drogan
had this big problem,
老男人多根有一个大问题
so he hired this man
to help him,
他雇用了一个人来家里帮忙
a very
professional man.
一个很专业的人...
It's already
taken care of, pal.
有人要付  先生
Here,
Mr. Halston.
你好  是霍司登先生吗
Here!
这里！
You are Mr. Halston,
aren't you?
你就是霍司登先生吧
That's me.
我是
Tell the driver
to wait.
请司机等一等
The man says
you should wait.
他叫你在这等着
For what this guy's paying,
I ain't going nowhere.
他没付我钱  我哪都不会去
Take your time.
你进去吧
In here,
Mr. Halston.
这里   霍司登先生
In here.
在这里
I want you
to make a hit.
我要你去解决掉一个人
That is what you do,
I understand.
就是你该做的事  明白吗
How did you
get my name?
你怎么知道我的?
A Mr. Saul Loggia
是从索尔罗杰先生那里
told me
that you know him.
得知的  你认识他  不是吗
Who do you
want hit?
要我去解决哪个人?
Your victim
is right behind you.
你要解决的对象
就站在你身后
I ought to
kill you for that.
我不搞这些
I don't like jokes.
我不开玩笑的
I don't make jokes.
我也不开玩笑的
Sit down.
坐下吧
Here.
这里
Sit down,
Mr. Halston,
请坐吧  霍司登先生
and look in
that envelope.
打开这个信封
$50,000.
五万美金
There will be
another 50,000
这只是一半的酬金
when you
bring me proof
另一半会在事成之后给你
that the cat has
ended its time on earth.
那只猫该从地球上消失了
I don't believe this.
真不敢相信
You're hiring me
to kill a cat?
你雇用我去杀一只猫?
That cat has
killed three people
那只猫已经杀了三个人
in this household.
在这栋屋子里
That leaves me.
现在只剩下我一个人
I need not
explain anything,
我其实不需要多作解释的
but I will.
但我还是得讲
In fact, I feel the need
to justify myself
事实上  这对我来说比较公平
so you won't
think me mad.
你不会想见到我发疯的
This is
quite a mansion,
这是一栋很大的别墅
don't you think,
Mr. Halston?
你说是不是  霍司登先生
Quite a mansion.
相当大
Help me up.
帮忙推一下
Over the years
在多年前
lfilled this place
with everything,
我深深爱上这地方
它的周遭每一件事物
everything
you could want,
且  只要我想要的
everything
you could ever want.
我都能如愿
There used to be
four of us living here...
我们家曾有四个人住在这里
myself
我
and Carolyn Broadmoor,
卡洛琳. 布罗迪摩
the only friend
of my sister Amanda.
她是我姐姐亚曼达唯一的好友
And Richard Gage,
a hired man
还有李查. 盖吉
他服伺我们
with the family
almost 20 years.
已有20年之久
We were
a dull collection
我们有相同的特性
of rich, old,
unhappy people.
都是一群富有, 老态
不快乐的人
Then...
然而
the cat came.
这只猫出现了
It was Gage
who saw it first.
盖吉是第一个发现猫的人
He tried repeatedly
to scare it away,
他试图想要把猫吓走
but every time
he drove it off,
但每次他把猫赶走后
it kept coming back.
猫还是一直回来
Finally,
直到后来
my sister Amanda
noticed the animal.
我姊姊亚曼达注意到它
She's the one
毕竟她很孤单
who took it in.
所以她收养了猫
Oh, the poor
little thing.
哦，可怜的小东西
It's starving.
它饿坏了
Is Oo hungry,
darling?
它很饿吗  亲爱的?
Is Oo hungry?
饿了吗
Cats aggravate
emphysema, Carolyn.
猫毛会让人过敏啊
卡洛琳
Get rid of
the filthy thing.
把这脏猫赶走
Cats aggravate
my brother, Carolyn.
猫会让我弟弟过敏啊  卡洛琳
Don't pay
any attention.
不用太在意
I want it
out of here!
我不要它在家里
Either out of here
or dead!
不是把它赶走  就是杀了它
Which is it to be?
你选一个
Don't you ever
你敢....
dare to hurt
this cat!
你敢伤害它  你就试试看
You hate cats.
You always have.
你恨猫  你老是这样
You're wrong.
I don't hate cats.
那你就错了  不是我恨猫
Cats hate me.
Don't you see?
是猫恨我  你不懂吗
We're all in danger
while this animal's here!
每次有猫的时候
我们就有危险
You'll find out!
你会发现的！你会发现！
You'll...
你会发现....
You all right?
你还好吧
I'll be fine.
我还好
我一会儿就好
You know who I am,
don't you?
你知道我是谁  是吧
That is, where
my money comes from?
也知道  我的钱是从何而来的?
Drogan Pharmaceuticals.
卓根制药公司
One of the biggest
drug companies
这可是最大的药厂
in America, Mr. Halston.
全美国最大的  霍司登先生
And the cornerstone
of our financial success
公司生产了一个王牌
奠定了日后的基础
has always been this.
而且也一直赚钱
Tri-Dormal-Phenobarbin,
三重苯巴比妥片
compound "G."
又称"复合性G"
Good old Tri-Dormal-G.
这种神效的复合性G群
A combination painkiller,
tranquilizer...
是一种安神的止痛剂
and mild hallucinogen.
伴随着温和的致幻药效
Remarkably helpful
to those of us fighting
值得注意的是
这药对我们老人是很有效的
the debilitating effects
of an aging heart.
虽然有破坏心脏的副作用
It's also
remarkably expensive.
但确实有显著的成效
It's also remarkably
habit-forming.
也因此  用药变成了一种习惯
I've read
all about it, Drogan.
我读过关于你们公司的相关报导
That stuff is one step
up from street junk.
那东西本来是一文不名
乏人问津
You've obviously
done very well with it.
你显然的  把它做了很好的宣传
And you've
done well yourself.
看来你做了不少功课喔
Saul Loggia knows of
at least two dozen jobs
你也知道我要雇个人
总有一堆人抢着要来
you have done for various members
of the professional community.
你为自己的专业  做足了准备
All right.
是的
We each know who it is
we're dealing with.
我们彼此都知道对方的底细
Tell me the rest
of the story
接下来  告诉我刚刚的故事
about that cat.
关于那只猫
Ah, yes.
啊 是的
The cat
killed them.
猫杀了他们
I warned them,
but they wouldn't listen.
我早就警告过他们  但他们不听
They found out.
首先
My sister
was the first to die.
第一个死的  是我的姊姊
It was midnight.
那是在深夜的时候
She was on her way
to the kitchen
她要下楼去厨房
to get that evil beast
some food.
只为了要喂那只邪恶的怪物
We heard her scream.
我们听到了她的尖叫声
Amanda?
亚曼达?
What happened, Amanda?
怎么了  亚曼达
Death by accident,
the coroner said.
警方说  她是意外致死....
But I knew.
但我心里可清楚了...
Why didn't you get rid
of the cat then?
那为何你不把猫赶走呢
I tried,
Mr. Halston.
我试过了  霍司登先生
I tried.
我试过好多次了
I'll kill it!
我要杀了这只猫
Let me have it!
我要杀了它
I'll kill it!
你别跑啊
Carolyn locked
the damn thing
卡洛琳竟然那鬼东西
in her room.
锁在她的房间里
She became obsessed
with the animal.
她对那只猫变得很痴迷
I'm going to kill it!
Do you hear me?
我要杀了它  听到没
I'll kill it!
I'll kill, kill, kill!
我要杀了它  杀了它  杀了它
My mother told me
我母亲在我小的时候告诉我
that cats like to get babies
and old people
猫会吸取老人跟小孩的灵魂
when they're asleep
and steal their breath.
当他们熟睡时
它们会来吸取人类的灵气
Carolyn died
at midnight as well.
卡洛琳同样在半夜身亡
Suffocated in her bed.
在床上窒息而死
The coroner said
natural causes in her case,
警方说  她因为年纪到了
算是自然死亡
but again,
但相同的厄运
I knew.
我心里有数
What did you do then?
后来你怎么做?
I told Gage to get rid
of the vile thing.
我要盖吉尽快把那家伙处理掉
It took him
almost 24 hours
花了一天的时间
to find the cat
and capture it.
好不容易才抓到它
Without concern
for the time,
好不容易...
I sent him out to Milford
to the veterinarian...
我要他把猫送到城里的兽医师那里
to have the beast put
away once and for all.
一劳永逸的把这只怪兽解决掉
I phoned ahead
to the vet.
我打电话给兽医。
"Mr. Drogan," he said,
他说  "卓根先生...."
"it's midnight."
"我得在半夜的时候做这件事"
（意即把猫安乐死）
A week later,
一个星期后，
the day Dick Gage
was buried,
就在我的仆人下葬的那一天
the cat came back.
猫回来了
No one actually witnessed
any of these deaths.
没有人知道这些人的死因
除了我...
What makes you think
你何以认为...
this cat had anything
to do with it?
这些事跟猫是有关连的?
I'm sure
it killed them.
我知道是猫杀了他们的
It killed
them all.
而我就是
And I'm next!
下一个！
I'm afraid of it,
Halston.
我害怕极了  霍司登先生
It skulks around
in the shadows,
它就像恐怖的黑影一样
watching me.
在暗处看着我
It's waiting.
等待着机会
It's torturing me
by waiting.
让我深受折磨
It's been sent
to punish me.
对我来说或许是一种惩罚
I don't get it.
惩罚?  我不懂....
Tri-Dormal-G.
就是这个药 - 三重苯巴比妥片
That's what
it's about.
这就是原因
It's a synthetic,
这是人工合成的
developed in our laboratories
in New Jersey.
当初实验室是设在纽泽西
Our testing
of Tri-Dormal-G
我们测试这款药的时候
was confined almost
solely to cats
我们用猫来做实验
because of
the unique quality
因为这款药品质独特
of the feline
nervous system.
利在猫科的神经系统中
可收取成效
How many
did you eliminate?
你们用了多少只来测试?
Over four years
of testing...
四年左右...
5,000 cats.
五千只猫
5,000 of your buddies
get wasted,
耗费了五千只猫来发展你的药...
and they send you back
to settle the score
所以这些亡魂派它来报仇....
with Drogan here,
跑到卓根家里来
is that the deal,
pussycat?
这就是代价啊  是不是啊  猫猫?
Don't make light
of it, Halston.
别鼓励它  霍司登
I warn you.
我警告你。
I never make light of any matter
involving $ 100,000.
我从来没干过这种事
我要十万美金
Then you'll
take the job?
这样你就会接这份工作吗
I could do it now
if you want me to.
我现在就可以完成  如果你想的话
I could put my hands
around its neck
我可以把手掐在它脖子上
and snap it.
只要用力一掐
Son of a bitch!
他妈的死猫
It's not going to be
that easy, Mr. Halston.
就跟你说  没这么容易
霍司登
Don't worry, Drogan.
你放心  卓根先生
I'll kill your cat
for you.
我来帮你把它终结掉
Good. Kill it, bury it
and bring me its tail
好  宰了它后  把猫尾巴带回来给我
so I can throw it in the fire
and watch it burn.
我要亲眼看到它被火融化
I'm going into the city.
我要出门去了
That's why I made
the taxi wait.
这就是为何我要计程车等着的原因
There's food, there's liquor,
there's everything.
房子里有食物  酒
你要吃什么  厨房都有
Everything
you could want.
你要什么就有什么
Everything
you could ever want.
你要什么我都可以给你
Okay, cat.
好了  猫仔
It's just
you and me now.
现在就剩下我跟你了
Jesus Christ.
上帝啊
Crazy old fucker.
真是疯狂的老头子
Crazy old rich fucker.
疯狂又富有的老混蛋
How about it,
kitty cat?
怎么了   猫仔?
"Everything
you could ever want."
你要什么就有什么
Why is it rich guys always
buy the cheap stuff?
怎么那么富有的老头子
会买这种廉价的酒呢
Look at this shit.
真是的...
Hey, cat!
嘿  小猫咪
For me, it's nothing
but the best.
对我来说  你可以让我大赚一笔
All the time.
来吧
"Everything
you could ever want."
好一个 "你要吃什么....都有"
Shit.
靠....
Hey, you little
motherfucker!
嘿  你这天杀的猫
Nobody hits me twice!
没有人可以伤我两次
No fucking body
hits me twice!
没有他妈的人可以伤我两次
Can't get hot.
不能发火
Can't let yourself
get hot, ever.
不能动不动就发火
You make mistakes
when you're hot.
一生气就容易犯错
What is this?
哇  这是怎么
What is this shit?
这是什么垃圾？
Oh, no!
噢, 不！
No!
不要！
This is a $ 100 shirt.
这可花了我一百美元耶
You'll be sorry
you messed with me,
你会后悔惹我的
you little shit.
你这该死的东西
I got a reason
to kill you now.
现在我可有理由来干掉你了
Drogan,
you cheap bastard.
该死的老房子
Come on, kitty cat.
Let's be friends again.
来吧  小猫咪
我们当个朋友吧
We can go over
by the fire like before.
我们停火好了
You can sit
on my lap again,
你可以坐在我的腿上
and I'll give you
a nice boost.
让我来抱抱你
This is the real stuff,
kitty cat.
这会真实的体验喔  猫仔
Not like that cheap crap
Drogan sells.
不像卓根家里这些廉价的垃圾食物
What do you say?
你说如何
You're beating me, pal.
你惹火我了
You're beating me good.
你真的惹到我了
I'm trying too hard.
我要来硬的了
Hey, cat...
嗨  猫咪
I've never
blown a hit yet.
我从不失手的
It's just a matter of time.
迟早会抓到你
Get away!
滚开
Get off of me!
你离我远点！
You're done for,
you fuck.
该是用枪的时候了   该死的东西
The rest
of your nine lives
看看你还有没有九条命
are going in one lump sum.
老话一句  我从不失手的
I can outwait you,
you little shit.
我就守株待兔了  死杂碎
I've never blown
a hit yet, kitty cat.
我从不失手的
This is the end of you.
你的末日到了
That's impossible.
不可能  不可能
Fucking impossible!
靠  不可能
I had a dead bead
on you.
我明明瞄准你的
Where are you?
你在哪里？
You son of a bitch,
I know you're in here.
死杂碎 我知道你在
Oh, no.
喔   不
No.
不!!
My goodness,
that was a scary story.
老天啊   好可怕喔
But my favorites
were the love stories.
但我最爱听的  还是爱情故事
Uh, yeah. There's one story
in that book that's really scary.
喔  我还有一篇恐怖故事
But it's
a love story, too.
但它也是一段爱情故事
Really?
是么？
Yeah.
嗯
Which one was that?
哪一段故事?
The one
that's in New York.
就那个在纽约发生的故事啊
You still have to cook
for quite a while,
反正你还有一点时间
but I'd love
to hear the story.
我想来听听看
"There's a part of New York
that's busy during the day,
好吧  这故事发生在纽约市
一个忙碌的工作天
"but late at night when
hardly anyone is around,
但晚上一到
街上都没什么人
"strange things
sometimes happen.
因此便发生了怪事
"10 years ago,
on a cold, dreary night,
十年前  在一个寒冷的夜晚
"an artist named Preston
有个叫做普林斯顿的艺术家
saw something
very, very strange."
他碰到了非常怪异的景象
Oh, yes. Wyatt.
喔  是怀特
Hello.
哈啰
Preston, it's Jer.
普林斯顿  我是杰
There's a guy here...
有个人在我这里...
Fortyish, anal retentive
type, right?
40多岁, 蛮龟毛的家伙是吧
On the money.
出手也蛮阔的
Tell him I've been waiting
half an hour.
麻烦告诉他  我已经等他半个多小时了
He's been waiting
half an hour.
他已经等你半个多小时了
Another Drambuie
on the rocks, please.
再来一杯  加冰块  谢谢
This one's on him.
这杯让他付...
4.50.
四块五
Keep it.
零钱别找了
Wyatt, I'm sorry.
怀特  抱歉了
I was just working
on a new piece.
我正在画一个新的作品
Ah, come here.
过来坐
Hey, Jer.
Give me a Holsten.
你好  杰
我要一杯霍斯顿
So, did you
bring me a check
你带支票过来了吗
or just a lot of cash?
还是直接带现金?
Thanks, Jer.
谢谢，杰
Judith says she hasn't moved
anything of yours in four months.
茱狄说她接下来四个月当中
无法展出你的作品
Judith Amato.
Big gallery on West Broadway.
茱狄. 阿芒托    她在西百老汇街
开了家画廊
If it isn't out by tomorrow,
it gets junked.
如果在明天没卖出的话  就变成垃圾了
What? Wyatt, you've got
to convince her that l...
你说什么? 怀特  你必须说服她
I can't convince her
of anything.
我无法说服她什么
Wyatt, you're my agent.
怀特...可是你是我的经纪人啊
Well, not exactly.
嗯  快不是了
Preston, your artistic vision
is just not a marketable commodity.
普林斯顿, 你的作品不符合
市场的商业性
Wyatt, I'm broke.
I can't live on nothing.
怀特  我已经破产了
我无以维生啊
And I can't live
on 10% of nothing.
我没办法  因为我抽不到佣金
You're a monster.
你真狠
I'm an agent.
在商言商
For an agent, being a monster
is just credentials.
身为一个经纪人
这是没办法的事
I'm sorry, Preston.
很抱歉  普林斯顿
Fuck you!
他妈的
Jesus, what am I
supposed to do now?
天啊  我现在该怎么办
Ah, Jesus.
天啊天啊
There's Van Gogh.
Degas. Rodin.
以前的梵谷  高更  罗丹
They didn't have agents.
他们都没有经纪人
How'd they
get so successful?
他们怎会那么成功呢
They died.
因为他们死了
Time to put it to bed,
Preston.
你该回家睡觉了  普林斯顿
All right.
好吧
What about Maddox?
那梅铎斯怎办
Let him out
in the morning.
明天再叫他走就好
That's probably
how I'll end up.
这可能是我的写照
Oh, jeez.
天啊
You're pissed
out of your mind.
你连站都站不稳
Ooh.
喔....
I'll take you home.
我陪你回去
All right.
好
Why didn't you
do that inside?
你为何刚刚不在里面尿啊?
I did. It just goes
right through.
我尿过了  只是又来一泡
Oh, my God!
天啊
Jer.
Help me.
请帮帮我。
Help me!
救命！
Jesus.
老天
Maddox!
Maddox, open the door!
梅铎斯  梅铎斯  开门啊
Help! Maddox,
open the door!
梅铎斯  开门开门
Please! Aah!
别这样
Please! Please don't!
求求你
Your life in exchange
for a promise.
我要用你的命  来换取承诺
You got it.
好  没问题
If I let you go,
如果我放你走
you must swear you'll
never say you saw me.
你要发誓你从没见过我
Never say
you heard me speak.
绝不能透露  你听过我的声音
Never tell anyone
how I look.
绝不能告诉别人
你看过我的样子
Never repeat
what I've said.
绝不能重复我说过的话
A promise forever.
永远的承诺我
You got to be kidding.
你在开玩笑吗
I... I... promise!
好  好  我答应你
Cross your heart?
用你的心来换
Ugh.
啊！
I promise!
我答应你
Come here.
你过来
No! Oh, God!
不要  不要
Shh! Shut up.
Please be quiet.
闭嘴  安静
Shh.
请你安静  嘘...
I'm not going
to hurt you.
我不是要伤你
Just be quiet,
all right?
只要安静就好  可以吗
All right?
I won't hurt you.
好吗   我不会伤你的
Let go of me!
那你就放我走
What are you
trying to do?
你想要干什么
Take a taxi.
我要搭车子
You don't see
any taxis out here, do you?
你有看到任何一辆计程车吗
If you want one,
如果你要搭
you can use the phone
from my place.
你可以在我家打电话叫车
Look, my name
is Preston.
听着  我叫普林斯顿
I live just
around the corner.
我住在对面转弯的街口处
Come on.
快跟我来
来啊
I thought someone
was following me back there.
我发现有人一直在后面跟踪我
That wasn't me.
不是我
Here we are.
到了
What are you
doing down here?
你怎么会来这里？
I was supposed to meet
some friends, but I got lost.
我来见一个朋友  但我迷路了
Here you go.
请进吧
So what were you doing
out this late?
这么晚了  你在外面做什么
I was having an argument.
我刚跟人吵架
My agent dumped me
tonight.
我的经纪人丢下我不管
Police, 16th Precinct.
Hello?
十六分局派出所   你好
Uh...
呃...
Anyone there?
有人在吗？
Jerk.
混蛋。
The line's busy.
忙线中
We'll try again
in a minute.
等一下再试试看
By the way...
what's your name?
对了  怎么称呼你
Carola.
卡拉
Can I have something
to drink?
我可以喝点东西吗
Sure.
当然。
So where are you
from, anyway?
那么你呢从哪里来呢？
Colorado.
科罗拉多州
Sort of.
附近
I had a boyfriend
in California.
我以前交了一个在加州的男友
But...
it didn't work out,
但  我们分手了
so I left.
所以我离开了
You're the first real artist
I've ever met.
你是我遇到第一个搞艺术的
Tell that to my agent.
呵呵  去跟我经纪人说吧
Did he do that?
你身上怎么会有...
I had a run-in
with a bottle of scotch.
我在酒吧跟人打架
I'm sorry.
对不起。
It's all right.
没关系。
I'm sorry.
很遗憾
Say, did you try
that taxi again?
那  你还要叫车吗
Maybe you should
wait till morning.
也许你可以等到天亮再走
Good morning.
早安
Last night was
very important to me.
昨晚对我来说  意义重大
It was a nightmare.
这是一场噩梦
Oh, no, Carola!
喔  不  卡拉
Not you!
不是说你
It was everything else
until I ran into you.
在遇见你前  我遇到一些事
That part was good.
你的部分是美好的
It was very good.
非常美好
I needed it.
我需要
I need more of it.
我需要多一点
I do, too.
Right now.
我也是   来吧
Oh, yes.
太好了
Help me!
救我
Oh, look.
听着
I have to go out
for a while.
我要出去一下子
Wait for me.
在这里等我
Hey, that's
my friend!
嘿  那是我朋友
That's my friend!
那人是我朋友
I want to go!
让我去看他
Someone cut off
his head!
有人把他的头砍了
Carola?
卡拉
Yeah. I would've
left, too.
是啊  我也很想离开这里
Help me!
救命啊
Yeah.
是谁
It's Carola.
卡拉
Can I come up?
我可以上来吗
Sure.
当然。
Jesus.
天啊
I know what
you're thinking,
我知道你在想什么
but the girl I'm staying with,
her boyfriend...
但我去看我的朋友  她的男友...
I didn't ask
any questions.
我不会过问你的
I called
a friend of mine...
我打电话给一个朋友
She's a friend
of a friend.
她朋友的朋友
She owns a gallery
on Houston Street.
在"霍斯登街"开了家画廊
That's
House-ton Street.
是"豪斯登街"才对
I told her how wonderful
I thought your work was,
我告诉她
我看到你的作品  非常的棒
so she'd like
to come see it.
所以她会过来看
Does she
have a name?
知道她的名字吗
Victorine...
维多莉亚
but I don't remember
the rest.
只知道她名字  其他就不知道了
Roget?
她姓罗杰?
Victorine Roget?
维多莉亚. 罗杰?
A friend
of a friend?
你朋友的朋友?
Jesus.
老天
I hope you don't mind.
希望你不会介意
Victorine Roget...
维多莉亚. 罗杰...
owns the hottest
gallery downtown.
在市区最红的名画廊
Of course
I don't mind!
我当然不介意
It's what
I've always wanted.
这就是我心所愿
So how does it feel
to be a huge success?
今天办的很成功   你知道吗
Victorine just sold
a piece to a couple for $23,000.
维多莉亚刚才用两万三千美元
把你的画卖给了一对夫妇
You're a smash.
这下你可红了
Well?
如何?
Damn.
该死
What?
怎了
Preston.
普林斯顿
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Hey, Maddox.
嗨  梅铎斯
Nice work.
干得不错！
Thanks.
谢谢
I haven't seen you
around, pal.
我好一阵子没看到你了  老兄
Not since
the night Jer died.
自从杰死的那晚之后....
I'm Carola.
我是卡拉
Nice
to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Who's Jer?
谁是杰?
The bartender
at this bar...
他是酒吧的调酒师
He died.
他死了。
In the alley
out back.
就死在酒吧门外
Come on. Let's go.
我们走吧
Hey, you know
something, don't you?
你知道发生了什么事  对吧
Just sober up, Maddox,
你别搅和  梅铎斯
before someone puts
a match to your breath.
不然我等等揍你
Preston.
普林斯顿
I told the cops
everything I knew,
警察已经盘问过我了
which is
exactly nothing.
我根本不知道发生了什么
Come on.
走吧
Promise forever.
承诺是永远的
So are you sorry
you met me?
你会后悔遇到我吗
You take care of me.
你很照顾我
Maybe just
a little bit...
也许  我也应该
I take care of you.
照顾你的  不是吗
Will you take care
of me... and my child?
那...你也会照顾...我的小孩吗
Your child?
你的孩子？
Oh, so...
难道是....
We going to make
this little bastard legitimate?
我们要合法的拥有小孩吧
To put it
another way...
我换个方式表达
will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me
like this?
你会嫁给我吗？
Oh, ho ho!
Yes, baby!
哦，呵呵！是的宝贝！
No! I'm pregnant!
不可以  我怀孕了
Come here,
sweetie!
过来我这里  宝贝
No, no, please!
不要啊
Where are
the scissors... scissors?
剪刀在哪里?
Mom, look what Wyatt
bought for me!
妈咪  看看怀特叔叔给我的东西
They took our picture
a million times.
已经拍很多张照片了啦
These kids
ran me ragged.
孩子们活力充沛
Each has the metabolism
of a hummingbird.
我追的好累
Ooh, is there some party
tonight that I'm missing?
喔  有人盛装打扮要去哪里?
Yes. Preston and I
are celebrating
是我跟普林斯顿要去庆祝
the 10th anniversary of
the night we first met.
我们认识十周年
When you thought he was
going to rape you?
从你们开始认识交往的那天算起吗?
Yes, darling.
It's also the night
是的   甜心  是在晚上
that Wyatt here gave
your father the shaft.
也是怀特离弃你爸的同一晚
I had to murder
three other agents
我还得击退另外三个人
竞争这位子
before you'd let me
represent him again.
直到你让我再回来  帮他服务
And you're still
on probation,
还有你仍在试用期喔  小心点
you mercenary wretch.
你这可怜虫
Find another agent
that'll baby-sit
你可以再找另一个经纪人来当保姆
the spawn of hell
on a Saturday night.
这样我周末晚上
就可从地狱重生
Wyatt!
怀特！
Choose your weapon.
选择你的武器。
10 years.
十年了
So many things
have changed.
世事已变迁
Changed for
the better, I hope.
我希望变的更好一些
The night I met you,
I almost died.
你遇到我的那晚  我差点就死了
What do you mean?
怎么说呢
Well, let's just say
就是说
it was the night
my life started over again.
那晚之后  我是浴火重生
So, happy anniversary.
那么，周年快乐
You know,
you saved Preston
知道吗   是你
从我这种人的手中
from people like me.
把普林斯顿拯救了出来
She saved me
from myself.
是她让我  拯救了我自己
Time to go.
总之  我告辞了
Sincerity is bad
for my self-image.
再说下去会破坏我自己的形象
Good night, Wyatt.
晚安  怀特
Good night,
Wyatt.
晚安
Whoa, taxi!
计程车
Taxi!
Let's move
to the country.
我们搬到乡下好吗
We'll buy
a big house
在那里买比较大的房子
with lots of land
for the kids.
小孩子也会有更大的空间
They'd hate it
as much as you would.
- 你给他们很多东西了
Then for you.
- 那你呢  你想要什么
There's nothing
you could give me
我想要的是你的内心
that I don't
already have.
这是你无法给我的
Yes, there is.
好  我现在给你
Oh, Christ,
I hate this neighborhood.
天啊  我讨厌这个鬼地方
Can't get
a cab here ever.
连台计程车都没有
No one has
ever seen this.
从来没有人看过这东西
That's what killed Jer.
就是他杀了杰
Then it turned on me.
然后  它过来要杀我
I knew
I was going to die,
我知道自己要死了
but it spoke. It spoke.
但那时候它说话了
It told me
it wouldn't kill me
它告诉我  留我活口可以
if I promised never
to tell anybody what I'd seen.
条件是  我答应永远不告诉别人
我见过它
So I never told anybody.
因此  我从来都不透露
Then why are you
telling me?
那你为何告诉我
Because you're the most
important thing
因为  你是我一生当中....
in my life.
最重要的人
You've brought me
10 years of happiness,
你带给我十年的快乐
10 years of success,
10年的成功，
10 years
of a perfect life.
10年的完美生活。
I'm telling you
because I love you.
我告诉你  是因为我好爱你
You deserve everything
I can give you,
你要什么  我都给了你
and I've never
given you the truth
只是我从不告诉你这件事情
about what happened
the night we met.
就发生在我们相遇的那个晚上
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I'm not
making this up.
我可没有危言耸听。
I'm telling you
the truth.
我说的都是实话。
You promised
you'd never tell!
你答应过   你永远不会说的
Ohh!
喔！
Oh, God.
天啊！
You broke your promise,
you idiot!
你破坏了承诺  你这笨蛋
I loved you!
我爱你！
Ugh!
哦！
Jesus, please...
老天  别这样对我
Carola, stop it!
Just change back.
卡拉  停下来  变回原来的样子
I can't.
不行，已经回不去了
No.
不
No!
What's wrong with the kids?
Stop it!
小孩子怎么办  别这样
It's too late.
太晚了
You betrayed
your vow.
你背叛了你的承诺
It can't be!
不可能的事
No!
不要！
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
Carola...
卡拉
I loved you.
我爱你
And I loved you, too,
我也爱你，
but you broke
your vow,
但你破坏了承诺
and that sealed
our destiny.
注定了我们未来的命运
Yo!
啊
Raarrr!
What the hell
was that?
这是什么东西 ！！！
I don't want to know.
我不想知道
My goodness, you really did keep
the best one for last.
老天爷  你把最好听的故事
放在最后一个讲
No. I saved the really,
really best one for now.
不  我这里还有一个更棒的故事
You should have told me
你应该早就要告诉我
the really, really
best story before,
这个最最最好听的故事了
'cause now
it's too late.
现在已经太迟了
It's the best one because
there's a happy ending,
但这个最好的故事
有个快乐的结局
a really happy ending.
是快乐的结局喔
The stories in that book
don't have happy endings.
书里的故事都没有快乐的结局啊
But you got to
hear this story.
你一定要听听这个
This kid,
his name's Timmy...
有个叫做堤米的小朋友
That's nice, dear.
很好  亲爱的
And Timmy's older brother
had this paper route.
而堤米的哥哥是送报童
One day, when
Timmy's brother got sick,
某一天  堤米哥哥生病了
Timmy had to go collecting.
堤米要帮哥哥去送报纸
Timmy went
to this one house,
堤米到了一栋房子前面
and this lady at the door
said, "Come in."
有个太太打开门说...进来吧
He went inside, and she
threw him into a pantry.
他进屋子后  那个太太就把他丢进厨房
She made him eat cookies
to get fat
她让堤米吃很多饼干  要养胖他
'cause she was going to
kill him and eat him!
因为这样就可以杀了他把他吃掉
This is your story,
这根本是你的故事
and we both know
how it comes out.
我们两人都知道结局会是如何
But you don't. Something
really weird happens.
但你不知道  会有怪事发生
Oh, really?
哦，是吗？
Yeah. Uh, Timmy
had these marbles
因为  堤米有很多弹珠
in his pocket,
在口袋里
and they were
all shiny and slippery.
它们圆滚滚又滑溜溜
When he threw them
on the floor...
当他把弹珠扔到地上
she didn't see
where they went...
她没看到
and she slipped!
她就滑倒了
Timmy saw his chance
to escape...
堤米便趁机逃亡
if he could just
reach the keys!
如果构得到钥匙
Don't you just love
happy endings?
你们喜欢快乐的结局吗？